ABOUT ME

After a 3.5 years period in Manufacturing Industry: firstly as a Project Engineer and then in Controlling Department, I have decided to pursue my career into Data Analytics.

After a successful Self Training period in Data Analytics I've joined Stuart a last-mile delivery scale up as an Operations Data Analyst and then as Product Analyst in Network Optimisation.

I'm looking for a Senior Data **Analyst Position**

LinkedIn **Self Training Portfolio**

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH - PROFESSIONAL WORKING



Paris. France

0770335537

kevin.assenza@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

STUART

Paris Aug 2022 - Present

Data Analytics

Product Analyst - Network Optimisation

Mar 2024 - Present

- Collaborated cross-functionally with Engineering, Product Management, and Design teams to develop a reactive software aimed at enhancing platform reliability through financial incentives and courier communications for 3 European markets
- Conducted Statistical Testing to extract actionable insights, informing and steering product development decisions.
- · Designed and implemented SQL pipelines alongside Tableau dashboards for comprehensive monitoring of critical product performance indicators.

Data Analyst - Operations

Aug 2022 - Mar 2024

- Engineered an automated Python solution for managing high-priority requests: GDPR, URSSAF and Government Indi cators and streamlining the Courier Digital Onboarding process and saving 20 hours per week for Operations.
- Engineered an automated Python-based earnings compensation model to assure a <u>minimal hourly</u> earnings for couriers in France
- · Collaborated with Operations to refine financial incentive strategies ~ 60k€ weekly, increasing profitability through data-driven optimizations.
- · Provided pivotal support to the Data Science team in the development and deployment of Machine Learning products into production environments.

CLAAS

Sep 2018 - Apr 2022

Manufacturing Industry

International Graduate Program - Finance & Controlling Aug 2021 - Apr 2022 - Germany Harsewinkel

- · Completed an intensive 4-month training in Controlling concepts acquiring foundational Finance skills
- · Advanced to a 6-month tenure at the Group's HQ in Germany: developed an automated Working Capital Dashboard and provided robust support in daily Controlling processes.

Industrial Project Engineer in Apprenticeship Sep 2018 - Aug 2021 - France Le Mans

- Developed and managed a reworking workshop for internal scraps with 4 part-time therapeutical employees - reduce scrapping cost by 50% ~ 250k€.
- · Developed two sub-assembly lines to reach new industrial concepts in order to increase production efficiency, quality and operator ergonomy ~200k€.

EDUCATION

SELF TRAINING

Paris 2022

Data Analytics

Portfolio - Self Training in Data Analytics: Python, SQL, Tableau, Statistics

ARTS ET MÉTIERS

Anaers 2021

Diploma equivalent Master of Science in Industrial

Master of Science in Industrial Engineering

Engineering - Ranking: 30/1200

LYCÉE CHAPTAL

Paris 2018

Preparatory Classes

Intensive post-Baccalaureat studies to prepare for competitive entrance exams to graduate Engineering schools